



# **Muhammad Moiz Siddique**

 Address: Flat no. B-805, Al Minal tower, Munawar Chorangi, Gulistan e Johar, Karachi, Sindh, 75200, Karachi, Pakistan

Email address: muhammadmoiz0087@gmail.com Phone number: (+92) 03062890575

**Website:** www.muhammadmoizsiddique.com

Whatsapp Messenger: https://wa.me/qr/HPOFY24MW2NAH1

Skype: live:muhammadmoiz2000991

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddique-74419b166/

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099">https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099</a>

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 09/05/2000 **Nationality:** Pakistani

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am a passionate and determined candidate who has transformed his hobby into a career, seeking an opportunity with a reputable organisation. I am an accomplished Senior Software Developer with over 3+ years of experience leading projects by acting as an architect, developer and programmer analyst. Proficient in supporting project deliverables and maintaining releases. Strong leader in guiding support teams and solving complex issues. Efficient in planning and implementing effective development strategies based on industrial best practices.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 01/06/2019 - 30/05/2022 ] **Associate Software Engineer** 

## **Algorack**

City: Karachi **Country:** Pakistan

## Main activities and responsibilities:

Thing I'm engage in here is with full stack technologies such as Angular Framework, React JS, Node JS, and others. I deal with clients, developed modules for frontend, backend and mobile apps, API integration, optimise angular JS and react JS code with modern approaches or industry best practices. The responsibilities further include code refactoring, testing with jasmine, karma and protractor and maintain the application structure. I got introduced to build systems such as gulp, babel, and webpack. I also got to work with no SQL (mongo dB with mongoose) databases and Node|S express backend applications with web sockets. I have further improved my verbal and written communication skills as I dealt with international clients along the way, mentoring and guiding junior and newly hired developers also helped in personal growth as well.

[01/09/2018 - 31/10/2018] Internship

Karachi Port Trust (KPT)

City: Krachi **Country:** Pakistan

### Main activities and responsibilities:

It was a great experience while working in one of the biggest organizations in Pakistan. I worked alongside some of the most skilled programming professionals, through whom I learnt (Dot)Net programming language. I was exposed to the software infrastructure used in such a large sized professional company. Through the skills I learnt, I was tasked with implementing further software creation and upgrading their existing software to improve upon the system. This opportunity also allowed me to thoroughly understand how Data Centers are utilized in such large organizations. This further helped me increase my teamworking creditability working within a professional IT department and understanding the workplace dynamic.



## **PROJECTS**

## [ 2017 ] 3D Canvas Simulation Using Javascript and html canvas

I have created a 3d simulated website using canvas and Three.js, which included various optical animations and fully animated graphs, all of that with a responsive design.

### [ 2018 ] JAVASCRIPT OCR (Optical Character Recognition)

I was very involved in discovering new thing in Javascript; therefore, I found an interesting opensource library named Tesseract, using that library I have created a website which extract text from the image.

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099/JavaScript\_OCR

## [2018] NOTES APPLICATION IN TYEPSCRIPT

I have created notes application in Javascript as my very first professional web application. In which, I have handled multiple features for notes e.g. change notes color, archive notes, arrange notes etc.

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099/My-Note-Application

### [2019] CAMERA APPLICATION USING JAVASCRIPT

I have created web camera application, in which, a video is started when website is opened and user can take a picture and the clicked picture shows below the video stream.

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099/JavaScript-Camera

## [2019] REACT JS SHOPPING CART

I have created a simple online shopping store application using React JS. It a simple application, in which, products are displayed, user can view the product, user can check out the product and user can proceed to payment.

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099/ReactJs\_Simple\_Shopping\_Cart

## [2019] FACE EMOTION DETECTION

I am always very curious in learning machine learning and data science. I found a library name Face API, I started study a lot on it and finally create a web application which tells your moods based on your facial expressions.

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099/Face-Detection

# [ 2019 ] WORKING ON WEB APP SOCIAL CHAMP (DOT) IO

I started working in a software house, where I got a project name social champ.io, Its structure based on Angular Framework. In this project, the idea is to merge multiple social media platform into one platform. For example, the twitter user can directly chat with Facebook user and similar with Instagram and vice versa.

https://www.socialchamp.io/

### [ 2020 ] WORKING ON WEB APP THINK EVOLVE SOLVE

In 2020, my project has been changed by the organization and later on I become the lead developer on this project. The idea of the project is to deliver advance data solution. The structure of the project is based on Angular Framework.

https://thinkevolvesolve.ie/



## [ 2021 ] WORKING ON WEB APP DXP FE-Component

In earlier 2021, my project changed. This project structure is based on Stencil JS And the wrapper is of React JS. In this project, my job was to create graphs and handle data visualization. The graphs are based on popular Javascript library named D3.JS.

https://www.dxpe.com/

## [2021] WORKING ON WEB APP CDP

After three months of DXP, when the graphs work is finished. My project changed to a new project. The structure of that project is based on React JS as Frontend and Node JS as Backend, I handle both the frontend and backend.

https://www.cdp.net/en

### [2021] WORKING ON WEB APP Fuse

My First own client project was Fuse, for which I worked as full stack developer. The structure of that project is based on Angular JS as Frontend and Nest JS as Backend, I handle both the frontend and backend.

### [2022] Bright Development

The idea of this project is to deliver a client development platform to a user, so the user can create his/her own website using the tools given in the platform according his/her needs. Basically, the platform provide the user a basic interface of a website and user can change it accordingly, like other CMS tools. I'm the lead frontend developer in this project and my job is to work on user stories and guide my team to work on the different part of the UI sections.

https://bright-development.com/

# EDUCATION AND TRAIN-

# [ 01/10/2017 - 18/07/2021 ] **Bachlor's in Computer Science**

Muhammad Ali Jinnah University https://jinnah.edu/

Address: Main Shahrah e Faisal, 22-E, Block-6, PECHS, 75400, Karachi, Pakistan

Field(s) of study: Computer Science (BSCS)

**Final grade:** CGPA 3.00 / 4.00

**Type of credits:** Credit Hours **Number of credits:** 132

**Thesis:** Journey Mate (JMate)

#### [ 01/08/2015 - 30/04/2017 ] Higher Secondary School Education (HSC)

Govt. Islamia Science College <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IslamiaScienceCollegeOfficial/">https://www.facebook.com/IslamiaScienceCollegeOfficial/</a>

Address: Karachi, Pakistan
Field(s) of study: Pre Engineering

**Final grade: 247/550** 

# [ 01/03/2013 - 30/04/2015 ] **Secondary School Education (SSC)**

Hyderi Public School https://www.facebook.com/Hps.pk/

Address: Saddar, 74400, Karachi, Pakistan

Field(s) of study: Science Final grade: 558/850



## CONFERENCES AND SEMI-NARS

### [ 2019 ] Conference on Game Programming – Un-Real Engine Karachi, Pakistan

I'm the Part of this conference as a listener. The basic purpose to attend this conference is to know that how people think on game ideas and how they present their game ideas and also for a new game demonstration.

### [ 2019 ] International Conference on Data Science (ICDS) Karachi, Pakistan

I'm the Part of this conference as an organizer. The basic purpose to attend this conference is to know that how people think on data science and how they present their ideas.

### **HONOURS AND AWARDS**

# [ 01/04/2020 ] **Programming in Python programming language Certification Awarding institution:** Hackerra

Completed the Python programming language course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/dbdb9e91627c

# [ 05/04/2020 ] **Programming in Javascript (Basic) programming language Certification Awarding institution:**Hackerrank

Completed the Javascript programming language course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c445d7643759

## [ 10/04/2020 ] **Programming in Java programming language Certification Awarding institution:** Hackerrank

Completed the Java programming language course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/7f2ae4930a2d

### [ 15/04/2020 ] Certification for Problem Solving Algorithms (Basic level) Awarding institution: Hackerrank

Completed the problem-solving Algorithms basic course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/af2f60ef934c

# [ 20/04/2020 ] Certification for Problem Solving Algorithms (Intermediate level) Awarding institution: Hack errank

Completed the problem-solving Algorithms intermediate course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/e887625f96ee

# [ 30/04/2020 ] Certification for Problem Solving Algorithms (Advance level) Awarding institution: Hackerran k

Completed the problem-solving Algorithms advance course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/f48c8558d84d



## [ 15/08/2020 ] Certification for Programming Rest APIs Awarding institution: Hackerrank

Completed the Rest API and microservices course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/9015bd3f83fb

# [ 13/09/2020 ] **Programming in C programming language (Basic) Certification Awarding institution:** Hackerr ank

Completed the C programming language (basic) course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/2045808c2786

# [ 26/09/2020 ] **Programming in C programming language (Intermediate) Certification Awarding institution:**Hackerrank

Completed the C programming language (intermediate) course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c3b3c6c02109

# [ 30/09/2020 ] **Programming in C programming language (Advance) Certification Awarding institution:** Hack errank

Completed the C programming language (advance) course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/c7bd28ed5199

## [ 10/01/2021 ] **Programming in C# programming language Certification Awarding institution:** Hackerrank

Completed the C# programming language course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/83d04b382305

# [ 07/08/2021 ] **Programming in Javascript language (Intermediate) Certification Awarding institution:** Hacke rrank

Completed the Javascript programming language (intermediate) course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/4e9849d2073a

# [ 14/08/2021 ] **Programming in Angular JS Framework Certification Awarding institution:** Hackerrank

Completed the Angular JS Framework course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test. https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/fbb44772f135

# [ 28/08/2021 ] Certification of UI/UX Designer CSS for designing websites Awarding institution: Hackerrank

Completed the CSS styling course, covered all the necessary topics and passed the test.

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/fc94abb7b587



#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1** 

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## **My Digital Skills**

Javascript | Html | Css | Python | Java | Angular | React JS | Stencil JS | Node JS | Express JS | Nest JS | Next JS | React Native | Aws Amplify | Graph QL | Material/Paper UI | Bootstrap | Tailwind CSS | Mobile Application (Android/IOS) | Firebase | C/C++ | Heroku | Cl/CD | Docker | Knex

#### **Educational Skills**

Google Drive | Microsoft Powerpoint | Critical and analytical thinking | Performance tracking | Gmail | Microsoft Office, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Outlook, Facebook, Google | Zoom | Resource Planning | Data Science, Data Analytics, Data Visualization

#### **Personal Skills**

Good listener and communicator | Written and Verbal skills | Attending briefs | Motivated | B rainstroming | Creativity | Idea Generation | Reliability

### **Admin Skills**

Process Management | Reporting using MS | Meeting Management | Marketing and Communications | Query handling | Target achievement

## **Organizational Skills**

Good listener and communicator; | programming, software engineering, software development | Decision-making | Adaptability for programming scripts based on the requirements of the projects | Quick problemsolving | Team - work oriented | Accepting responsibility | Strategic planning. | Ability to learn quickly, listen and communicate with others correctly. | Attention to details | Organization planning and punctuality | dynamic, seeks new challenges and opportunities for professional growth and advancement | Excellent communication skills gained through my experience in a big team with many customers. | Confident team player, thriving on challenge | Prioritise tasks, Supervise work, and Develop strategy to solve problems | Motivated and ambitious | Good team spirit, good intrapersonal and interpersonal relationships | Ability to Work under Pressure | Logistical organisation | Organizati onal and Planning Skills | Good at being proactive and efficient in high stress situations | Good leadership skills, planning and collaboration in heterogeneous groups

## NETWORKS AND MEM-BERSHIPS

[06/04/2018 - Current] Linked In

Became member of Linked in community in 2018.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-moiz-siddique-74419b166/

[ 11/05/2018 - Current ] **GitHub** 

Became member of GitHub community in 2018.

https://github.com/MuhammadMoiz200099



## [ 19/07/2019 - Current ] **Stack Overflow**

Became member of Stack Overflow community in 2019.

https://stackoverflow.com/users/10478682/muhammad-moiz

## PERSONAL AND PROFES-SIONAL CHARACTERISTICS

#### **KEY COMPETENCES**

- Good English and Urdu in written and verbal communication.
- Dynamic, Friendly, Self-motivated and Target oriented personality.
- Capable to handle business correspondence independently.
- Experience of working under pressure with speed and accuracy.
- Good skills and ability to deal successfully with technical and non-technical
- o clients.
- Quick learner and problem-solving skills
- Thriving to continuously improve personally and professionally.
- Excellent team-player with good cooperation and interpersonal skills.

### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

## Interests

- Speed Programming competitions
- Learning new courses/certifications
- Travelling
- Poetry
- Guitar/Music
- Football
- Puzzles and games
- Streaming